Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to go over how to create a level unlock system.
So by default, we'll make it to the player can play level one.
But in order to play level two with the boss, our player character is going to have to have beaten
level one.
To set up that system.
If we go over to our main menu widget blueprint.
And go to the designer, select the first button and copy it and then duplicate it again inside of this
level box and select the first button and add a padding of 50.
That way there's a bit of a gap at the padding in the right.
And if I just select this text, I'm going to call this level two.
And if we select this button and scroll down and go unclipped, we are only going to open the next level.
If our player has beaten level one, we can do that referencing the safe system that we just made.
So if we drag in the same ref, we want to drag up here and look for get levels.
I just drive up here and look for get a copy and we want to get a copy of level one and we want to check
to see the value of this Boolean drag.
Okay.
And look for Branch.
And if this is false, then we're going to do nothing.
However, if this is true, then we're going to open a level one aim and that level is going to be my
boss level.
So I call the boss map.
So here I'm going to type in boss map.
And now if I go compile and save, I'll only be able to open this level if I beat in level one.
If we go back to our player save.
I realized that I accidentally made it so that we've already beaten level one.
So if we just leave this unchecked and go compile and save, this isn't going to actually override the
save game that we just made because we've already told the save game that we've beaten number one.
So we need to delete our save game in order to delete a save game inside of Unreal Engine.
We can just right click and go show in Explorer.
This will open up our project in Windows mode and just go to whatever you call the project, so called
my action platformer and we're going to see this photo called Saved Head Inside here and then go to
save games, then go to the saved game folder here inside of this folder.
Unreal Engine is going to keep a log of all our saved games.
So I called my save game one.
Just select it and then go delete.
Then if we close this and if I go back to my main menu level.
I'll save everything.
And good play is going to create me a new set game.
And in my new save game, I made it so that I've not beaten level one.
So now if go, start and try and get level two, it's not going to open because I've not beaten never
one.
The next thing we need to do is make it so that we can beat level one.
If I just close this and go to the item folder and go over to the item image order and briefly close
on our engine and attached in this lecture, I'm going to make sure to include the sign error.
Just drag it into your Android engine project.
And just right click and go Sprite actions apply paper to DX and then create a Sprite out of this image.
Then if we go to our item folder, we're going to create a new blueprint.
If we just right click and Go Blueprint class, select actor and call this level unlock.
If we open this up.
And go ahead and look for a paper spread.
I'm going to select the sign that will just imported.
And I'm going to scale up a bit to a three.
And just make sure its collision is no collision.
And we're going to add a box collision around the sprite.
So look for box collision.
And make sure it fits around our papers.
Right.
Then we scroll down and go on the component.
We can overlap if this overlaps or play a blueprint.
So drag a player and the forecast to play a blueprint.
And we are going to drag up here and get that same reference.
So, look, forget play or save.
Then if we just drag up here and look for get levels.
I'm drug repair and look for a set array element.
Right click on this index and promote it to rebel and call it level number.
And make sure this is instance editable and just check this item and connect the nodes here.
So the idea here is we made this array which has loads of elements.
So it has an on one element too.
And if we want, we can add more elements.
When our play a character is in level one, we're going to type in one inside of this value.
And when I play a character beats this level.
We're going to set element one to be true.
That's why we just want to make sure this is checked.
And that's why we have this variable which will help us determine which element inside of this array
we should check.
So for level one, we'll set this to one and for level two.
We'll set this to two.
After we do this, we just need to make sure to save this.
So if we drag off here and look for safe game to slot and our slot name is one.
And then after we do this, we're going to have a delay.
Or let's say one second.
And then we are going to open them by name.
And then we can open the next level, just right click on this value, promote it to rebel and call
this level name.
I make an instance editor and go compile.
If I close this, if I go to the end of level one and I just place this level or not at the end of my
level.
So around here, I'll just move this to layer 20.
And it's actually very small.
So if we go back in here.
Let's scale it up so I'll make it ten.
Okay, that looks a bit better.
And under level number, type one and under level name will make it so that when we beat this level,
we're taken to the boss level.
So I called that boss map.
So here, under level name, I'm going to type in boss map.
And we can save this and test this out.
So if I go to my main menu, go save and go play.
Start and then try and click on level two.
I can't.
But if I click on level one, it will open and take me to that level.
I'm now just going to quickly get to the end of this level.
Okay.
So I made it to the end of my level.
When I go here.
And one second it's going to take me to level two.
And now I'm in level two and I should have unlocked level one.
So if I just pause this and go to my main menu.
I can now go start.
Then click level two.
Okay, so it looks like I have an error.
It says access non trying to read the safe reference in my main menu so look at branch.
Ah.
Okay.
Yes.
My fault.
Okay, so in my event construct, if our safe game does not exist, then we create the safe reference.
However, if our safe game does exist, then we don't do anything.
So we just need to create a safe reference.
If our save game does exist.
So if I just drag off true and not full load game from slot, the slot name is going to be one and then
I'm going to cost to my platform to save.
And then we can track and I'll save reference and set it and just connect the notes here.
That way, if I do have a save game, I'll create my save game reference.
So now if I go compile and play and I go to my main menu because I'd be in number one, I should be
able to open level two.
So if I select this, it will take me to level two and everything is working fine.
Let's do one more thing because our level two is kind of different.
Let's make it so when we beat the boss and level two, it will tell the game that we beat in level two.
If I go back to my boss blueprint.
If we just open up our blueprint before we destroy our boss, what we're going to do is just right click
and forget player character.
From here, we can cast to our player blueprint.
And from here we can get our Plan C reference.
So I look for get player save.
And from here I can look for get levels.
And then we can juggle, pay and look for a set array element.
And the index is going to be two because our boss is in level two.
If your boss is in a different level, then you can set this to be a different value.
We can just check this item box and connect the nodes here.
And then we just want to save this to our safe game.
So I drive up here and look for safe game to start.
The start is going to be one.
We can then hook this up here and destroy this actor.
And actually, instead of destroying this actor, we can go open up opening.
And then I'll take my player back to the main menu.
And now just to test this out, I'm going to give my boss one HP and go compile and I'm going to go
to level two.
Sorry, the boss map.
And I'm going to kill him quickly.
So I killed him.
He's destroyed.
And then it will take me to my main menu.
Okay with that?
We've created a level and not system.